Muhammad Faizan

App Developer (Native Android + Flutter)

44000

mohammadfaizan980@gmail.com

+92 341 9299464

An app developer and a designer with 3 years of development experience. I work in both, Native Android (Kotlin) and Flutter App Development. In native android development, I use jetpack compose instead of XML.

I have tendency to learn and adapt new things quickly. For example, I learned Node.js when I needed to work on some APIs, learned Figma when needed to demonstrate a UI concept with prototype, learned Strapi when a project required me for that, learned SDUI when a project needed and many more examples.

Work Experience

App Developer (Flutter + Kotlin)

Safarifone - Islamabad February 2022 to Present

Currently working here as a full time app developer, working a native android app using jetpack compose, app will connect with vending machines for providing POS services using serial communication with the vending machine and also raspberryPi connection for machines which do not allow direct communication with internal hardware. Along with that, I am also working on a flutter app for the hosts, who will provide their property for hosting the vending machine for public use. Also sometimes doing UI/UX designing and prototyping.

Flutter Developer

Tentwenty Digital - Islamabad March 2021 to February 2022

Worked here as a full time flutter app developer with periodic backend work for APIs development with Node is

Flutter/Android Developer

Infusible Coders - Kohat February 2019 to March 2021

Worked here as native android and flutter app developer and worked on variety of apps mainly using google maps, InApp payments, stripe, REST APIs, Firebase services.

Education

BSCS

Kohat University of Science and Technology 2016 to 2020

Skills

- Flutter
- Kotlin
- Java
- Dart
- MVVM
- Providers
- Rest APIs
- Stacked
- Location Services
- Sockets
- Bluetooth Communication
- Firebase (storage, auth, social auth, firestore, realtime DB)
- Google Maps
- Leaflet.js Maps aka Flutter Map
- SDUI

Languages

- Urdu Expert
- English Intermediate

Links

https://muhammadfaizan980.github.io/

https://www.linkedin.com/in/muhammad-faizan-5054aa164/